

 $\searrow$ 

ihar.yazerski@outlook.com

+375447513822

Q

Minsk, Belarus

in

linkedin.com/in/iharyazerski

(7)

github.com/igorezersky

## **SKILLS**

RESTful API (wsgi/asgi)

Message Queuing

Swagger

Crawling

Docker

CI/CD

NLP

ML

Project managing

## **LANGUAGES**

English

Intermediate

Russian

Proficient

Belarusian

Proficient

### **INTERESTS**

Traveling

Management

Football

Snowboarding

# Ihar Yazerski

Senior Python Developer

Senior Python developer with a strong background in computer science and ML. Specializing in API development and NLP. Skilled in Docker, RabbitMQ, FastAPI, Flask, Starlette, Celery, Scrapy, Telegram bots, Pandas, Jupyter, Numpy, Gensim, Spacy, and Scikit-Learn. Experienced in DevOps and created own deployment approaches.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Python Developer Globant

08/2021 - Present

A digitally native company that helps organizations reinvent themselves to create a way forward and unleash their potential

# **Data Scientist**Silk Data

05/2018 - 08/2021 Minsk

Develops software products based on natural language processing and artificial intelligence, provides software development and deployment services

#### Proiects

- Briefly a free augmented search summary for Google. Briefly gives you only the essence of search results by squeezing exact data in just one click.
- <u>TextSimilarity</u> solution based on NLP algorithms to match and combine pieces of textual content based on a degree of their semantic similarity.
- <u>TextSegmentation</u> powerful solution for fast and quality contracts analysis based on text segmentation via ML model initially prepared on a set of documents with manually labeled clauses.
- Semantic Search ML based solution where algorithms analyze large volumes of texts to extract meaning of separate fragments, explore different topics and how they are related to each other and to a user's context.

Minsk

# **Data Scientist**CIB Software

09/2017 - 05/2018

Creation of software for standard word processing systems

Proiects

- participated in multilingual OCR engine development
- vacancies analysis system for HR specialists

# **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

### pydeployhelp

pydeployhelp is aimed to help integrating deploy (via Docker) to Python projects. It can be used both as external library (all processors can be imported) and as CLI tool

## pyRandSeqBot

pyRandSeqBot is a Telegram bot. It randomly generates a queue for the entered list (for example, the order of speakers at the meeting). The entered data will be saved for future use.

### WeatherAPI

WeatherAPI is a small and simple weather API, created as a pet project to demonstrate my skills in API development. This API allows receiving weather (temperature, wind, cloudiness, etc.) for specified city

### **EDUCATION**

**Information systems and technologies (Software Engineer)**Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics

09/2015 - 07/2019 Minsk